道格
Doug?
親愛的 你還好吧
Honey, are you all right?
你又做夢了 道格
You were dreaming. Doug?
是否又是關於火星的夢
Was it about Mars?
好點沒
Is that better?
我可憐的寶貝
My poor baby.
這些夢都快佔據你的腦袋了
This is getting to be an obsession.
她也在夢裡嗎
Was she there?
誰
Who?
那個你對我提過的褐髮女子
The one you told me about. The brunette.
羅莉
Oh, Lori.
我不敢相信連我作夢你也會吃醋
I can't believe you're jealous of a dream.
- 她到底是誰  - 無足輕重的人
- Who is she?  - Nobody.
無足輕重的人 她叫什麼名字
"Nobody"? What's her name?
我不知道
I don't know.
- 告訴我  - 我不知道啊
- Tell me!  - I don't know!
你最好告訴我
You better tell me!
這可不好笑 道格 你每天晚上都夢到她啊
It's not funny, Doug. You dream about her every night.
但我到了早上總會回到你身邊
And I'm always back in the morning.
放開我
Let me go!
別這樣 寶貝
Come on, baby.
你知道你才是我夢想中的女孩
You know you're the girl of my dreams.
你這是真心話
You mean it?
你很清楚我是真心的
You know I do.
讓我給你的春夢提供些題材
I'll give you something to dream about.
主席為這次攻擊辯護 宣稱在太空中佈署的武器
The chairman defended the attack, saying that space-based weapons
是唯一能對付南區新興勢力的有效防禦
are our only defence against the southern block's numerical superiority.
此外 火星昨晚又發生暴亂
And more violence last night on Mars
要求獨立的恐怖份子
where terrorists demanding independence
再度迫使T礦的開採停工
once again halted the extraction of terbinium ore.
寡頭和他率領的所謂自由戰土
Kuato and his so-called freedom brigade
宣稱這次爆炸事件是他們幹的
claimed credit for this latest bombing,
企圖重新開啟已封閉的金字塔形礦坑
which attempted to reopen the sealed-off Pyramid Mines.
火星軍事當局僅以最少的兵力就恢復當地秩序
Mars military restored order with minimal use of force
所有重要的戰略設施都在一小時內修復完畢
and all damage to the strategic facility was repaired within hours.
不准拍攝
No cameras!
目前已經有一處礦坑關閉 火星行政官維羅斯·柯黑根
With one mine already closed, Mars administrator Vilos Cohaagen
宣稱在必要時仍將動用軍隊
vowed that troops would be used if necessary
以維持足額的開採量
to keep production at full capacity...
難怪你會做惡夢 你老喜歡看新聞
No wonder you're having nightmares. You're always watching the news.
- 羅莉  - 道格
- Lori.  - Doug?
- 咱們就這麼辦吧  - 做什麼
- Let's do it.  - Do what?
搬到火星去住
Move to Mars.
你為什麼一定要破壞一個如此美好的早晨呢
Honey, why do you have to spoil a perfectly wonderful morning?
考慮一下吧
Just think about it.
親愛的 我們已經談過無數次了 你會討厭住在火星上的
Sweetheart, we've been through this a million times. You'd hate it on Mars.
那裡既乾燥 醜陋 又無趣
It's dry, it's ugly, it's boring.
更何況 那裡隨時都可能爆發革命
I mean, really, a revolution could break out there any second.
柯黑根說那只是一小撮偏激份子
Cohaagen says it's just a few extremists.
你相信他的說法
You believe him?
好吧 就當我沒提過此事
OK. Forget about it.
絕對不行 火星是北區投下大量經費才殖民成功的
Absolutely not. Mars was colonised by the northern block at enormous expense.
我們全部的軍費都得依賴此地的T礦開採
Our entire war effort depends on their terbinium.
就只因為一些懶惰的變種人而將這一切放棄是荒唐的想法
It's ridiculous to think we'd give it away just because some lazy mutants...
道格
Doug
- 或許咱們該去做一次旅行  - 羅莉 拜託別擋住銀幕
- Maybe we should take a trip.  - Lori, move, please.
還有許多比火星更好的地方啊
There's a lot better places than Mars.
土星怎樣 你不想到土星去看看嗎
What about Saturn? Don't you wanna see Saturn?
大家都說那裡好漂亮
Everybody says that its gorgeous.
事實是寡頭先生和他的恐怖份子企圖散佈這些謠言
Fact is, it's Mr Kuato and his terrorists who spread these rumours
以損害人民對政府的信任
to undermine trust in the government.
我們可以做一次長途太空之旅
We could take a long space cruise,
那種無須刻意做任何事的旅行
the kind with nothing to do.
- 你們找到寡頭了嗎  - 我們還不知道他長什麼樣
- Have you found Kuato yet?  - We don't even know what he looks like.
- 你說什麼  - 我快遲到了 羅莉
- What do you say?  - I'm late, Lori.
親愛的 道格
Sweetheart. Doug.
我知道剛搬到一個新城市是很難適應的
I know it's hard being in a new town,
但請你試試看 好嗎
but let's give it a chance, OK?
羅莉 你難道不明白嗎
Lori, don't you understand?
我覺得我這輩子不該只是如此
I feel like I was meant for something more than this.
我想在我的一生中有番作為 我想成為一個有用的人
I want to do something with my life. I want to be somebody.
你已經是個了不起的人了
You are somebody.
你是我愛的男人
You're the man I love.
再見
Bye.
祝你有個愉快的一天
Have a nice day.
你現在正進入一個安全地帶
You are now entering a safety zone.
所有經核准的武器 都不得攜出檢查點
No unauthorised weapons allowed beyond this point.
你現在正進入一個安全地帶
You are now entering a safety zone.
所有未經核准的武器 都不得攜出檢查點
No unauthorised weapons allowed beyond this point.
你是否夢想到雪地去滑雪 但卻苦無門路
Would you like to ski but you're snowed under with work?
你是否夢想到海底悠遊...
Do you dream of a vacation at the bottom of the ocean,
卻付不起旅費
but you can't float the bill?
你是否渴望到火星上爬山...
Have you always wanted to climb the mountains of Mars...
但你的體力卻已經走下坡
...but now you're over the hill?
那就到瑞可公司來吧
Then come to Recall Incorporated
你在此可以買到你心目中理想的假期
where you can buy the memory of your ideal vacation
比真正的旅遊經驗更便宜 更安全 更好
cheaper, safer and better than the real thing.
別讓美好的人生從你眼前溜過
So don't let life pass you by.
立刻撥電話到瑞可來
Call Recall for the memory of a lifetime.
給你的生命留下美好的回憶
For the memory of a lifetime
瑞可...
Recall, Recall, Recall
哈利
Harry.
- 你聽過瑞可這個公司吧  - 瑞可
- Harry! You ever hear of Recall?  - Recall?
就是專門賣假記憶的地方
Where they sell those fake memories.
是啊 瑞可 瑞可...
Oh, Recall! Recall, recall, recall!
- 你想去找他們  - 我不知道 或許吧
- Thinking of going there?  - I don't know. Maybe.
- 別去  - 為什麼
- Well, don't.  - Why not?
我有一個朋友試了他們的特殊產品 結果腦前葉被切除了
A friend of mine tried one of their special offers, nearly got himself lobotomised.
真的
No shit?
別拿自己腦袋開玩笑 兄弟 不值得
Don't fuck with your brain, pal. It ain't worth it.
我想是吧
I guess not.
你好
Hello.
下午好 歡迎光臨瑞可公司
Good afternoon. Welcome to Recall.
我是道格拉斯·奎德 和醫生約好了
Douglas Quaid. I have an appointment.
- 鮑伯  - 是的
- Bob?  - Yeah?
- 道格·奎德來找你了  - 我馬上來
- Doug Quaid is here to see you.  - I'll be right out.
好
OK.
請稍待一下 奎德先生
That'll be just one minute, Mr Quaid.
謝謝你
Thank you.
- 道格 我是鮑伯·麥克連 幸會  - 幸會
- Doug! Bob McClane. Good to see you.  - Nice to meet you.
到裡面談吧 這邊請
Come on in. Through here.
坐 不必拘束
Go and have a seat. Make yourself comfortable.
謝謝你
Thank you.
告訴我 道格
Now, help me out here, Doug.
- 你想要植入的記憶是關於...  - 火星
- You were interested in a memory of...  - Of Mars.
是啊 火星...
Yeah. Mars.
有困難嗎
Is there a problem?
我老實告訴你好了 如果你對外太空感興趣的話
To be perfectly honest with you, Doug, if outer space is your thing,
我想你會更喜歡我們的土星之旅
you'd be much happier with one of our Saturn cruises.
這是目前最流行的
Everybody raves about them.
不 我對土星沒興趣 我要的是火星
No. I'm not interested in Saturn. I said Mars.
好吧 花錢的人是大爺
OK. You're the boss.
那麼就設定在火星
Mars it is.
我看看...
Now, let me see.
一次標準的火星之旅 收費是899個信用單位
The basic Mars package will run you 899 credits.
這包括整整兩個禮拜的記憶 不但完整 而且非常詳細
Now, that's for two full weeks of memories, complete in every detail.
如果你要更久的時間就得再加錢 因為我們得植入更深
If you want a longer trip, that'll cost you more cos it's a deeper implant.
兩個禮拜的旅程裡包括什麼
What's in the two-week package?
首先 當你到瑞可來
First of all, let me tell you. When you go Recall,
所得到的絕對是第一流的記憶
you get nothing but first-class memories.
在太空梭上接有私人包廂
Private cabin on the shuttle,
住宿希爾頓的豪華套房 加上到所有觀光點遊覽
deluxe suite at the Hilton, all the major sights:
金字塔山 大運河 當然還有維納斯城
Mount Pyramid, the Grand Canals and of course, Venusville.
但這些記憶將有多逼真
But how real does it seem?
- 和你自己的記憶一樣逼真  - 少來 別忽悠我了
- As real as any memory in your head.  - Come on. Don't bullshit me.
我是說真的 你的大腦將分不出它有何差別
No. I'm telling you, Doug. Your brain will not know the difference.
信用保證 不滿意可以退錢
And that's guaranteed or your money back.
被你們切除腦前葉的那傢伙呢
What about the guy you lobotomised?
你們事後有退錢給他嗎
Did he get a refund?
這是好久以前的事了
You're talking ancient history.
在今天 以瑞可的方式旅行 比搭火箭安全多了
Nowadays, travelling with Recall is safer than getting on a rocket.
你看看那些統計數字
Check out those statistics.
更何況 一次真正的旅程再麻煩不過了
Besides, a real holiday is a pain in the butt.
你會遺失行李 碰上壞天氣 還會被計程車司機敲竹槓
You got lost luggage, lousy weather, crooked taxi drivers.
但當你以瑞可的方式旅行時 一切都是完美的
When you travel with Recall, everything is perfect.
你說怎樣
So, what do you say?
- 好吧  - 明智的決定
- All right.  - Smart move.
好 在你填這份調查表的同時
All right, while you fill out this questionnaire,
我順便向你介紹一下其他的產品
I'm going to familiarise you with some of our options.
不要其他的產品
No options.
隨便你好了 我能問你一個問題嗎
Whatever you say. Can I ask you just one question?
在你以往每次的旅行中
What is that is exactly the same
都有哪一樣共同點
about every single vacation you have ever taken?
我放棄
I give UP
你 你就是那共同點
You. You're the same.
不論你到哪裡去 你總是同一個你
No matter where you go, there you are. It's always the same old you.
我建議你這回暫且不當你自己
Let me suggest that you take a vacation from yourself.
我知道這聽來很玄
I know, it sounds wild.
這是我們最新的旅行方式 我們稱它叫"自我旅行"
It is the latest thing in travel. We call it the Ego Trip.
不 我對這沒有興趣
No. I'm not interested in that.
你會喜歡它的 道格
You're gonna love this, Doug.
我們提供你以不同的身份去旅行
We offer you a choice of alternate identities during your trip.
幹嘛以觀光客的身份到火星去 你可以花花公子的身份去
Why go to Mars as a tourist, when you can go as a playboy?
- 或是著名的運動員 或...  - "秘密情報員"
- Or a famous jock or...?  - "Secret agent."
這要多少錢
How much is that?
讓我來對你詳細解說一下
A-ha! Let me tantalise you.
你是個第一流的情報員 喬裝臥底執行你最重要的任務
You are a top operative under deep cover on your most important mission.
黑白兩道的人馬都在追殺你
People are trying to kill you. Left and right!
美麗的異國情調的女人
You meet this beautiful, exotic woman.
說下去
Go on.
我不想破壞你到時候享受的樂趣
I don't wanna spoil it for you, Doug,
但我向你保證 在旅程結束時
but by the time the trip is over,
你將獲得美人的芳心 殺光壞人 拯救整個星球
you get the girl, kill the bad guys and save the entire planet.
你說說看 這不值得花三百個信用單位嗎
Now, you tell me. Isn't that worth a measly 300 credits?
- 這是你的第一次旅行  - 嗯
- Your first trip?  - Mm-hm.
別擔心 咱們這裡很少出差錯的
Well, don't worry. Things hardly ever fuck up around here.
晚安 道格
Good evening... Doug.
- 我是樓醫生  - 幸會
- I'm Dr Lull.  - Nice to meet you.
厄尼 連結第62B及37號的細胞問質
Ernie, patch in matrix 62-B-37.
還有 你想增加些外星怪物嗎
And would you like us to integrate some alien stuff?
好啊 有何不可
Sure. Why not?
- 雙頭怪物  - 你從來不看新聞嗎
- Two-headed monsters?  - Don't you keep up with the news?
我們現在研究外星人的史前古跡
We're doing alien artefacts now.
看起來真古怪
It's wild.
是啊 它們有數百萬年的歷史
Yeah, they date back a million years.
- 厄尼  - 這玩意是新的
- Ernie?  - That's a new one.
- 火星上的藍色天空  - 結婚很久了
- Blue sky on Mars.  - Been married long?
- 八年了  - 噢 我明白了
- Eight years.  - Oh, I see.
背著老婆出來找些刺激
Slipping away for a little hanky-panky.
- 不完全是 我一直對火星感興趣  - 系統運行
- No. I'm fascinated with Mars.  - All systems go.
我們可以開始了
Then we're set.
準備進入夢鄉了
Ready for dreamland?
首先我要問你幾個問題 這樣我們才能適當調整自我之旅
I'll be asking you some questions so we can fine-tune the Ego program.
你若能老實回答 你的旅程就會更加愉快
You answer honestly, you'll enjoy yourself a whole lot more.
- 你的性活動傾向是什麼  - 異性
- Your sexual orientation.  - Hetero.
好 你喜歡什麼樣的女人
So, how do you like your women?
金髮的 褐髮的 紅發的
Blonde? Brunette? Redhead?
褐髮的
Brunette.
苗條的運動員型 肉感型
Slim. Athletic. Voluptuous.
運動員型
Athletic.
端莊型 侵略型 輕佻型
Demure. Aggressive. Sleazy.
- 老實回答  - 輕佻型
- Be honest.  - Sleazy.
端莊型
Demure.
41A 厄尼
41A, Ernie.
他將度過一段狂野的時光
Boy, is he gonna have a wild time.
- 他會不想回來  - 這是一定的
- He's not gonna want to come back.  - Oh, that's for sure.
那麼...
So...
你說呢
what do you say?
我難以決定 連個紀念品也沒有
I'm not so sure, and I don't get a souvenir.
也不儘然 你只要加些額外費用
Not true. For just a few more credits
我們就提供T恤 以及你在觀光點拍的照片
we supply T-shirts, snapshots of you at the site,
甚至信件...
and even letters from...
- 什麼事  - 你最好快來這邊一下
- What is it?  - You'd better get down here.
我正在和一個重要客戶談生意
I am with a very important client.
看來咱們又碰上另一個精神分裂症患者
Looks like we got another schizoid embolism.
- 我馬上回來  - 麥克連先生
- I'll be right back.  - Uh... Mr McClane?
- 麥克連先生  - 鮑伯 出了什麼事
- Mr McClane?  - Bob! What's wrong?
別讓她走掉
Don't let her leave!
滾開
Get off!
你們暴露了我的身份
You blew my cover!
你連個簡單的植入手術都做不好
What's going on? You can't do a simple goddamn double implant?
不是我的錯 他的記憶有問題
It's not my fault we hit a memory cap.
他們隨時會到 他們會殺了你們
They'll be here any minute! They'll kill you all!
- 他在說些什麼  - 放開我
- What is he talking about?  - Let me go!
奎德先生 試著冷靜下來
Mr Quaid, try to calm down!
我的名字不叫奎德
My name is not Quaid.
- 讓我走 快替我鬆綁  - 厄尼 抓住他的腿
- Let me go! Untie me now!  - Ernie, grab his leg!
- 放開我  - 快拉住他
- Untie me!  - Hold him down!
放開我
Let me go!
你沒事吧
Are you all right?
聽我說 他一直不停地說著火星的事
Listen to me. He's been going on and on about Mars.
- 他真的到過那裡  - 用你的腦袋想想 你這笨女人
- He has really been there.  - Use your head, you dumb bitch.
他剛剛的表現正是自我旅行中的情報員角色
He's just acting out the "secret agent" portion of his ego trip.
- 這恐怕是不可能的  - 為什麼
- I'm afraid that's not possible.  - Why not?
因為我們根本還沒將記憶植入
Because we haven't implanted it yet.
慘了
Oh, shit.
這下可慘了
Oh, shit!
這正是我要告訴你的 有人洗掉了他的記憶
I've been trying to tell you, someone has erased his memory.
對不起 你是說"某人"
Excuse me. "Someone"?
我們在談論該死的情報機構
We're talking about the fucking Agency.
- 閉嘴  - 鮑伯 那個客戶走了
- Shut up!  - Bob, the client's gone.
好 好 聽我說 咱們就這麼辦
OK, all right. All right, look. Here's what we're going to do.
我們將他所有關於瑞可的記憶通通洗掉
Renata, cover up any memory he's got of us or Recall.
我盡力而為 他的記憶亂成一團
I'll do what I can. It's pretty messy in there.
厄尼 把他搬下去 送上計程車 蒂凡妮 你幫他
Ernie, dump him in a cab around the corner. Tiffany, you help him.
我要毀掉他的資料 退回他的錢
I'm gonna destroy his file and refund his money.
如果有人找上門來 就說我們從沒聽過道格·奎德
And if anybody comes asking, we never heard of Douglas Quaid.
我在哪裡
Where am I?
- 你在一輛強尼計程車上  - 我怎麼會在這裡
- You're in a Johnnycab.  - What am I doing here?
對不起 你能換個方式問這問題嗎
I'm sorry. Would you please rephrase the question?
我怎麼會坐上這輛計程車
How did I get in this taxi?
車門打開 你就上了車
The door opened, you got in.
累了一天 是吧
Hell of a day, isn't it?
- 這裡可以吧  - 停在這邊
- This OK?  - Right here.
- 多謝你搭乘強尼計程車  - 謝謝你
- Thank you for taking Johnnycab.  - Thank you.
希望你滿意我們的服務
Hope you enjoyed the ride.
嗨 奎德
Hey, Quaid.
- 哈利  - 你的火星之旅如何
- Harry.  - How was your trip to Mars?
- 什麼旅行  - 你到瑞可公司去 還記得吧
- What trip?  - You went to Recall. Remember?
- 我有嗎  - 是的 你去了
- I did?  - Yeah, you did.
- 我叫你別去 但你偏要去  - 你是誰 我爸爸
- I told you not to, but you went anyway.  - What are you, my father?
- 來吧 我請你喝一杯  - 聽著 我已晚到家了 謝謝你
- Come on, I'll buy you a drink.  - Listen. I'm already late. Thank you...
好 帶上他... 快點
OK, bring him... Come on, move it!
咱們這就去喝一杯 快
Let's go get that drink. Move it!
這到底是怎麼回事 我到底做錯了什麼
What the hell is going on? What the fuck did I do wrong?
- 告訴我啊  - 你亂說關於火星的事
- Tell me!  - You blabbed about Mars!
你瘋了嗎 我對火星一無所知啊
Are you crazy? I don't even know anything about Mars!
你該聽我的話 奎德 我試著讓你別惹上麻煩
You should've listened to me, Quaid. I was there to keep you out of trouble.
哈利 你這麼做可就錯了 你將我誤認為某個人
You're making a big mistake. You got me mixed up with somebody else.
不對 兄弟 是你誤認自己是某人
Uh-uh, pal. You got yourself mixed up with...
拋 發球
And pivot... and serve...
收拍 抽球
and shift... and stroke... and pivot.
發球 收拍 抽球
And serve... and shift... and stroke.
很好 完美的動做
Very good. Perfect form.
發球 收拍 抽球
And serve... and shift... and stroke.
親愛的
Hi, honey.
- 你在幹什麼  - 剛剛有幾個人想殺我
- What are you doing?  - Some men just tried to kill me.
搶匪 你沒事吧
Muggers? Are you all right?
不 他們是間諜之類的
No, they were spies or something.
還有我的同事哈利 他... 快蹲下
And Harry from work, he was the... Get down!
- 我的同事哈利 他是帶頭大哥  - 道格 冷靜下來 好嗎
- Harry from work, he was the boss.  - Take it easy, Doug, OK?
把事情的經過詳細地告訴我 為何會有間諜想要殺你
Tell me exactly what happened. Why would spies want to kill you?
我不知道 但和火星有關
I don't know. But it had something to do with Mars.
你沒到過火星啊
You've never been to Mars.
我知道這聽來很荒唐 但我今天去了瑞可公司...
It sounds crazy, but I went to this Recall place after work...
- 你跑去找那些腦科殺手  - 先讓我把話說完
- You went to those brain butchers?  - Let me finish.
- 他們把你怎麼了  - 我到火星旅遊了一次
- What did they do to you?  - I got a trip to Mars.
- 結果...  - 哦
- So what happened...  - Oh...
別管瑞可的事 行不行 那些人想殺我啊
Forget about Recall. Will you? These guys were going to kill me.
- 道格 沒有人想殺你  - 他們想殺我
- Doug, nobody tried to kill you.  - They did.
但我殺了他們
But I killed them.
聽我說 親愛的...
Listen to me, sweetheart.
那些瑞可的混蛋弄壞了你的腦袋
Those assholes at Recall have fucked up your mind.
你開始產生偏執的幻想
You're having paranoid delusions.
你說這也是幻想嗎
You call this a delusion?
道格
Doug
- 我要打電話叫醫生來  - 不 別打電話給任何人
- Doug, I'm gonna call a doctor.  - Don't. Don't call anybody.
你好
Hello.
羅莉 快走 離開這裡
Lori, go! Get out!
羅莉
Lori?
羅莉 你為什麼要這麼做
Why are you doing this, Lori?
說 我叫你說
Talk! I said talk.
- 我不是你太太  - 你不是才怪
- I'm not your wife.  - The hell you're not.
我發誓我六個禮拜以前沒見過你
I never saw you before six weeks ago.
我們的婚姻只是植入的記憶
Our marriage is just a memory implant.
你認為我是個笨蛋 我記得我們的婚禮
You think I'm stupid? I remember our wedding.
那是情報局植入的記憶
It was implanted by the Agency.
- 戀愛  - 植入的
- Falling in love.  - Implanted.
我們的朋友 我的工作 八年在一起的時光
Our friends, my job, 8 years together.
難道這些也全是植入的記憶
All of this was implanted too?
工作是真的 是情報局替你安排的
The job's real. The Agency set it up.
狗屁
Bullshit.
他們抹掉你的身份 植入一個新的
They erased your identity and implanted a new one.
我被安排來當你的太太 以便就近監視
I was written in as your wife so I could watch you
確定你的記憶被徹底洗乾淨
and make sure the erasure took.
抱歉 奎德 你這一生只是一場夢
Sorry, Quaid. Your whole life is just a dream.
好 如果我不是我 那麼我又是誰
OK, then if I'm not me, who the hell am I?
問倒我了
Beats me.
我只是奉命來這裡工作
I just work here.
道格
Doug
道格 我要你知道一件事
Doug, there's something I want you to know.
你是我出過的任務中最棒的 我是說真的
You were the best assignment I ever had. Really.
我感到很榮幸
I'm honoured.
念在往日的情份上 你真的不要再來一次嗎
You sure you don't want to, just for old times' sake?
來吧 如果你不信任我 可以把我綁起來
Come on. If you don't trust me, you can tie me up.
- 我不曉得你原來這麼變態  - 或許你也該知道這點了
- I didn't know you were so kinky.  - Maybe it's time you found out.
好聰明的女孩
Clever girl.
你該不會真的開槍吧 道格 咱們畢竟夫妻一場啊
You wouldn't shoot me, would you, Doug? After all we've been through.
的確有些愉快的時光...
Some of it was fun.
很高興認識你
Nice knowing you.
別碰她
Don't touch her.
屋裡沒人
Nobody here.
- 你沒事吧  - 我想我壞了大事
- Are you OK?  - I guess I blew it.
- 他想起了什麼  - 到目前為止 什麼也沒有
- What does he remember?  - Nothing, so far.
我追蹤到他了
I've got him.
糟糕 他朝地下鐵的方向去了 咱們追上去
Shit, he's going for the subway. Let's get him. Go.
咱們走 快
Let's go. Move it.
收拾行李離開這裡
Pack your stuff and get outta here.
如果他們把他抓回來呢
What if they bring him back?
這是不可能的
Not a chance.
地下鐵 快
Subway! Go!
抓住他 他身上有槍
Get him! He's got a gun!
- 堵住他的去路  - 那邊
- Cut him off! That way!  - Over there!
- 站住  - 別動
- Hold it!  - Don't move!
自動扶梯
The escalator.
你們四個上去 你跟我來
You four go up. You come with me.
閃開 閃開
Get out of the way! Come on!
Get out of the way! Move!
月臺
The platform!
- 哪邊  - 右邊
- Which way?  - To the right.
巴科 明日的燃料 明日的價格
Botco. Tomorrow's fuels, tomorrow's prices.
別滿足於蒼白的回憶 別被騙去植入假記憶
Don't settle for pale memories or fake implants.
以傳統方式享受一次美好的假期
Experience space travel the old-fashioned way
人人享受得起
on a real, live holiday you can afford.
我要那王八蛋死
I want that fucker dead.
我能體會你的心情 我也不願意讓奎德這種人玩我的老婆
I don't blame you. I wouldn't want Quaid porking my old lady.
你是說她喜歡這麼做
You saying she likes it?
不 我認為她痛恨和他在一起的每一刻
No, I'm sure she hated every minute.
請接柯黑根先生的傳真電話
Six-beta-nine, we have a live transmission from Mr Cohaagen.
- 我是瑞克特 傳過來  - 請講 柯黑根先生
- Richter here. Patch it through.  - You're on, Mr Cohaagen.
- 這到底是怎麼一回事  - 我正在追殺一個叛徒 長官
- What the fuck is going on?  - I'm trying to neutralise a traitor, sir.
你這白癡 如果我要他死 就不會將他丟在地球上
If I wanted him dead, you moron, I wouldn't have dumped him on Earth.
我們不能讓他到處跑 他知道太多的秘密
We can't let him run around. He knows too much.
羅莉說他什麼也不記得
Lori says he can't remember jack shit.
現在是如此 一小時後他將完全恢復記憶
That's now. In an hour he could have total recall.
給我聽著 我要你將奎德活著送回來 重新植入記憶
Listen to me, Richter. I want Quaid delivered alive for re-implantation.
你聽清楚了沒
Have you got that?
我要他回去跟羅莉重聚
I want him back in place with Lori.
你聽見了沒
Did you hear me?
長官 你說什麼 我聽不見
What was that, sir? I couldn't hear you.
- 你在幹什麼  - 我追蹤到了奎德
- Richter, what are you doing?  - I got Quaid again.
轉到另一個頻道 長官 有太陽黑子干擾
Switching to another channel, sir. I've got sunspots.
- 給我回電話 給我回電話  - 我無法接收到你了
- Call him back! Call him back!  - I'm losing you.
- 他在哪  - 加星利區 第二層
- Where is he?  - Second level, galleria.
你該在火星上就把奎德幹掉的
We should've killed Quaid on Mars.
"麗池大飯店"
- 信號的接收狀況呢  - 好極了
- How we doing?  - Fine.
我現在將它放大 鎖定住他了
Zooming in... We got him!
如果你想活命 就別掛斷
If you want to live, don't hang up.
- 你想怎樣  - 你身上有追蹤器
- What do you want?  - They've got you bugged.
他們在三分鐘後就要破門而入
They'll be busting down your door in about three minutes
除非你照我的話去做
unless you do exactly what I say.
不必找了 追蹤器在你的頭裡
Don't bother searching. The bug's in your skull.
- 你是誰  - 別管我是誰
- Who are you?  - Never mind.
找條濕毛巾包在頭上 可以減弱訊號
Wet a towel and wrap it around your head. That'll muffle the signal.
- 你是如何找到我的  - 我奉勸你最好快點照辦
- How'd you find me?  - I'd advise you to hurry.
這可讓你爭取一些時間 他們將無法鎖定你
This'll buy you some time. They won't be able to pinpoint you.
該死
Shit!
- 怎麼回事  - 我追丟他了
- What?  - I lost him.
- 再給我找  - 好的
- Well, find him!  - Yeah, right.
快點 你看來很正點
Come on. Hurry up. You look beautiful.
現在到視窗去 快去
Now go to the window. Go.
- 看得見我嗎  - 嗯
- Can you see me down here?  - Mm-hm.
- 這是你交給我的那口箱子  - 我交給你的
- This is the suitcase you gave me.  - I gave you?
我把它放在這裡 你到下面來拿 然後繼續走
I'm gonna set it here. You come and get it, keep moving.
- 慢著 等一下  - 什麼事
- Wait. Wait.  - What?
- 你是誰  - 我是你在火星情報局時的同事
- Who are you?  - We were buddies in the Agency.
你說過你若是失蹤的話 就來找你 所以我來了
You asked me, if you disappeared, to find you, so here I am.
我在火星上時是做什麼的
What was I doing on Mars? Damn!
對不起 太太 這是我的
Excuse me, ma'am, but this is mine.
- 上面又沒寫你的名字  - 是人家留給我的
- I don't see your name on it.  - Someone left it for me.
- 去找你自己的箱子  - 對不起 太太 我真的需要它
- Find your own bag.  - Excuse me, ma'am, but I need it!
去你的 你這王八蛋
Fuck you, you asshole!
那狗娘養的一定就在這附近
Son of a bitch gotta be here somewhere.
那邊那傢伙
That guy there.
哈羅 我是強尼計程車 今晚上哪去
Hello, I'm Johnnycab. Where can I take you tonight?
開車 開車
Drive. Drive!
- 麻煩你重複一下這地址好嗎  - 上哪去都行 開車就是了
- Please repeat the destination.  - Anywhere! Just go! Go! Go!
請說出一個街名和號碼
Please state the street and number.
媽的 媽的
Shit. Shit!
我沒聽過這個位址 能否請你重複...
I'm not familiar with that address. Would you please repeat...?
系上你的安全帶
Fasten your seat belt!
車資一共是18個信用單位
The fare is 18 credits, please.
去告我好了 笨蛋
Sue me, dickhead.
希望你滿意我們的服務
We hope you enjoyed the ride.
你好 陌生人 我是豪瑟
Howdy, stranger. This is Hauser.
如果事情出了差錯 我如今就得對著自己說話
If things have gone wrong, I'm talking to myself
而你則得在頭上包著濕毛巾
and you've got a wet towel wrapped around your head.
不管你叫什麼名字 下面這事實包准叫你大吃一驚
Now, whatever your name is, get ready for the big surprise.
你並不是你 你其實是我
You are not you. You are me.
別廢話
No shit.
6B9 6B9 請回答
Six-beta-nine, six-beta-nine, come in.
你找到他了
Did you find him?
我們掃瞄到廢棄的水泥工廠 發生了一場爆炸
We picked up an explosion at the old cement factory.
- 派兩組人過去 咱們在那裡碰頭  - 知道了
- Send two units. We'll meet you there.  - Roger.
我這輩子都在火星情報部工作
All my life I've worked for Mars Intelligence.
替柯黑根做了許多傷天害理的事
I did Cohaagen's dirty work.
但幾個禮拜前我遇到一個人 一個女人
But a few weeks ago I met somebody, a woman,
她讓我覺悟到一些事
and I learned a few things.
比方說 我是在助紂為虐
Like I've been playing for the wrong team.
我現在能做的 就是好好彌補一下過去的罪擎
All I can do now is try to make up for it.
這個腦袋裡裝的東西 可以讓柯黑根死得很慘
There's enough shit in here to fuck Cohaagen good.
不幸的是 如果你聽到這段話 就表示他已經先一步整倒了我
Unfortunately, if you're listening to this, that means he has got to me first.
最困難的部份就在此 兄弟
Here comes the hard part, old buddy.
從現在起全得靠你了
Now it is all up to you.
真是太好了
Great.
- 你們找到了什麼  - 車上沒有人
- What have we got?  - Nothing here.
- 他已經走了  - 我抓到前方有微弱的訊號
- He's gone.  - I got a weak signal over there.
散開 把他找出來
Split up. Find him.
首先 將你頭裡的追蹤器取出來
First let's get rid of that bug in your head.
將這東西從箱子裡拿出來 然後插進你的鼻子裡
Take this thing out of the case and stick it up your nose.
別擔心 它是自動導向的
Don't worry. It's self-guiding.
用力插進去就行了
Just shove real hard.
當你聽到一個碎裂聲 那就是了
When it crunches, you're there.
將它拉出來
Just pull it out.
但要小心 那也是我的腦袋
Be careful. It's my head too.
- 我鎖定住他了  - 在上面 咱們上
- I've got a lock.  - Up. Let's go.
我的計畫是這樣的...
This is the plan.
你到火星上去
Get your ass to Mars,
然後到希爾頓飯店 出示一份布魯貝克的證件給櫃檯接待員
then go to the Hilton and flash the Brubaker ID at the desk.
如此就行了
That's all there's to it.
照我的話去做
Just do what I tell you.
咱們兩個就可以讓那個狗雜種得到應有的制裁
And we can nail that son of the bitch who fucked you and me.
我全靠你了 兄弟
I'm counting on you, buddy.
可別讓我失望
Don't let me down.
正前方
Straight ahead.
在這裡面
In there.
那邊
There!
給我
What? Give me that.
到火星上去
Get your ass to Mars.
- 到火星上去  - 他媽的
- Get your ass to Mars.  - Shit.
到火星上去 到火星上去
Get your ass to Mars... Get your ass to Mars...
歡迎光臨火星聯邦自治區
Welcome to the Mars Federal Colony.
為了各位的健康和舒適 我們建造了圓頂
For your safety and comfort, domes have been installed
以隔絕外界的真空環境
to protect you from the vacuum outside.
請不要碰觸外側的窗戶或氣閘
Please do not touch exterior windows or air locks.
由於本地的空氣供應量極為有限 此地全面禁止吸煙
Air volume is limited. No smoking is allowed anywhere in the colony.
下一個
Next.
謝謝各位 祝你們在火星的停留期間愉快
Thank you, and enjoy your stay on Mars.
護照呢
Passport.
快點 閃一邊去 讓路 退後
Get out of the way. Make way! Stand back!
柯黑根先生要見你 馬上
Mr Cohaagen wants to see you right away.
有奎德的消息嗎
Any news of Quaid?
- 自從你追丟他之後就沒有了  - 講話當心點 上尉
- Not since you lost him.  - Watch your mouth, Captain...
- 你打算在火星上停留多久  - 兩個禮拜
- So how long do you plan to stay?  - Two weeks.
看看那上面寫的
Look at that shit.
- 這他媽的又是什麼  - 火星的人民愛戴寡頭
- What the hell's this?  - The Martians love Kuato.
他們以為他是華盛頓再世
They think he's fuckin' George Washington.
宰了這混蛋
Kill the bastard.
沒人知道他到底是誰
Nobody knows who he is.
你有攜帶任何水果或蔬菜嗎
Have you brought any fruits or vegetables?
兩個禮拜
Two weeks.
你說什麼
Excuse me?
兩個禮拜
Two weeks.
Two weeks!
那不只是普通的塗鴉 叛軍昨晚攻佔了煉製廠
It's not just graffiti. The rebels took over the refinery last night.
所有的T礦都無法輸出
No terbinium is going out.
情況還會更嚴重
And it gets worse.
奎德
Quaid.
- 那就是奎德  - 哪裡
- That's Quaid!  - Where?
那個女人 把他抓起來 我是說"她"
The woman! Get him... her!
逮捕那女人
Arrest that woman!
抓住那女人 攔住她
Get that woman. Grab her!
接住
Catch!
準備大吃一驚吧
Get ready for a surprise!
- 把這該死的門打開  - 我辦不到
- Open the goddamn door!  - I can't!
把它打開
Open it!
這些門和氣閘是連接在一起的
They're all connected!
真可怕
That's terrible.
而且前幾天柯黑根又提高了空氣的價格
A few days ago Cohaagen raised the price of air.
又一次
Again?
地球上的人根本不管我們死活
Nobody on Earth gives a damn what happens up here.
他們只要T礦 好能夠去打他們那無聊的戰爭
They just want our terbinium so they can fight their war.
對不起 那是什麼
Excuse me. What's that?
你是指那金字塔礦場
You mean the Pyramid Mine?
我在那裡工作過 直到他們在裡面發現外星人留下來的東西
I used to work there until they found that alien shit inside.
這不是傳聞而已嗎
Well, that's a rumour, isn't it?
你認為如此
Think so?
柯黑根先生
Mr Cohaagen.
長官 你有事找我
You wanted to see me, sir?
瑞克特
Richter...
你知道我為何如此快樂嗎
Do you know why I'm such a happy person?
不知道 長官
No, sir.
因為我有全太陽系最棒的工作
Because I've got the greatest job in the solar system.
只要T礦一直生產下去 我就能做任何我想做的事
As long as the terbinium keeps flowing, I can do anything I want.
任何事
Anything
事實上 我唯一擔心的事只是
In fact, the only thing that I ever worry about
若有那麼一天 叛軍獲得了勝利 這一切就可能隨之結束...
is that one day, if the rebels win, it all might end...
而你卻要造成這種結果
and you're fucking making it happen!
首先你企圖殺奎德 然後你又讓他逃掉
First you try to kill Quaid, then you let him get away.
他有我們的人暗中幫助 長官
He had help from our side, sir.
這我知道
I know that.
- 但我以為...  - 誰叫你想
- But I thought...  - Who told you to think?
我可沒給你足夠的資訊來思考
I don't give you enough information to think.
你只要奉命行事就行了
You do what you're told. That's what you do.
是 長官
Yes, sir.
現在...
Now...
咱們開始來談正事
Let's get to business.
我們面臨一個難纏的局面
We've got a tricky situation here.
寡頭要奎德腦袋裡所知道的東西
Kuato wants what's in Quaid's head.
而且他也有可能得到 因為傳聞他有心電感應的能力
And he might be able to get it, cos they say he's psychic.
而我已想出一個計畫來阻止他成功
And I have a plan to keep this from happening.
你認為你這回可以好好合作嗎
Do you think you could play along?
- 是的 長官  - 好極了
- Yes, sir.  - Great.
否則 我就會取你的狗命
Cos otherwise, I'll erase your ass.
先生 你要坐計程車嗎 我的車上有雜誌 音樂 威土忌
Taxi? You need a taxi, sir? I got magazines, music, whisky.
老兄 要搭計程車嗎 來吧
Hey, man, you need a cab, man? Come on! Come on!
"希爾頓飯店"
下午好 有什麼我能效勞嗎
Good afternoon. Can I help you?
是的 麻煩你給我一個房間
Yes, I would like to have a room, please.
歡迎再次光臨 布魯貝克先生 你要同一間套房
Nice to have you back, Mr Brubaker. Would you like the same suite?
當然
Oh, definitely.
你似乎有東西放在保管箱裡
Seems you've left something in our safe.
能否麻煩你將它拿來給我
Could you get it, please?
我們要核對身份
Identification?
- 我這就去拿你房間的鑰匙  - 謝謝
- I'll encode your room key.  - Thank you.
"終極樂園"
"享受好時光 請找梅琳娜"
- 鑰匙在這裡 西大樓的610號房  - 謝謝
- Suite 610 in the east wing.  - Thank you.
- 我能借用你的筆嗎  - 當然
- Could I borrow your pen, please?  - Certainly.
"梅琳娜"
謝謝你
Thank you.
老兄 坐計程車嗎
Hey, man, you need a cab?
這一輛的服務會比你差嗎
What's wrong with this one?
他可沒有要養五個孩子啊
He ain't got five kids to feed.
- 你的車在哪兒  - 就在那邊 兄弟
- Where's yours?  - Right over there, man.
嘿 哥們
Hey! Hey, man.
王八蛋 這是我的客人啊
Hey, asshole! That's my fare!
- 一邊涼快去  - 班尼 你這該死的...
- Eat this!  - Damn you, Benny!
歡迎光臨火星 兄弟
Welcome to Mars, man!
剛剛那是什麼 意外事件
What the hell was that, an accident?
是反抗軍幹的 咱們快離開此地吧
That's the rebels, man. Let's get outta here...
否則待會就會被捕
Before they arrest us!
反叛軍要的是什麼
What do the rebels want?
和往常一樣 更多的錢 更多自由 更多空氣
The usual. More money, more freedom, more air.
上哪去
So, where to?
終極樂園
Last Resort.
才剛到就迫不急待了
You're getting off to an early start.
- 第一回來火星  - 是的
- First time on Mars?  - Yes.
事實上... 不是 也可說是
Well, actually, no. Well, sort of.
老天 連自己是否來過火星都弄不清楚
The man don't even know whether he's been to Mars or not.
這就是了 維納斯城
Voila. Venusville.
看到中意的貨色沒
Ha, ha! Hey, you see anything you like?
車子只能開到此 我們接下來最好用走的
Well, this is the end of the line. We'd better walk from here.
我帶你到那地方去
I'll show you where.
- 想知道你的未來嗎  - 過去呢
- Do you want to know the future?  - What about the past?
來吧 就在轉角的地方 就在這巷子裡
Come on. It's around the corner, right down this alley.
他們這裡什麼都有
They got everything.
不錯吧
Notbad,huh?
看手相 讀你的心思 你的欲念 你心裡的秘密
Read your palm? Your mind? Your aura? Probe the secrets of your heart?
我打賭我猜得出你的生日
I bet I can guess your birthday.
- 你是金牛座的 對吧  - 你怎麼猜到的
- You're a Taurus, right?  - How did you guess?
- 告訴我 所有的通靈人都是...  - 變種
- Tell me, are all psychics...?  - Freaks?
全是變種 是這一帶的特產
Afraid so, man. It goes with the territory.
他們怎麼會變成這樣
What happened to them?
廉價的圓頂 又沒空氣來阻擋有害的射線
Cheap domes, no air to clean the rays.
咱們到了 終極樂園 你真的要在這間玩嗎
So, this is it. The Last Resort. You sure you want to go in here?
- 有何不可  - 我認識另外一家更好的
- Why not?  - There's a better place down there.
女孩子比較乾淨 酒也不摻水
The girls are cleaner, the liquor ain't watered down...
是啊 你還可以拿到回扣
Sure, and you get kickbacks.
兄弟 我有五個孩子要養啊
Hey, man, I got five kids to feed.
帶他們去看牙醫吧
Take them to the dentist.
謝了 先生 聽我說 我在外面等你
Hey, thanks, mister! I'll be waiting for you.
你慢慢玩好了 我叫班尼
You just take your time. Benny's the name.
- 要什麼  - 我找梅琳娜
- What do you want?  - I'm looking for Melina.
她現在很忙
She's busy.
找馬麗好了 她有空
But Mary here, she's free.
不是免費 親愛的 而是...
Well, not free, honey, but...
有空
...available.
謝謝 我還是等梅琳娜好了
Thanks. I'll wait for Melina.
地球無賴
Earth slime.
問題是 梅琳娜對客人是很挑剔的
Thing is, friend, Mel's real picky.
她一向只招待熟客人
She kind of sticks to her regulars.
她會喜歡我的
She'll like me.
梅琳娜
Mel!
嘿 梅琳娜
Hey, Mel!
你好 豪瑟
Hello, Hauser.
看得出你仍是全身鼓脹如昔
Still bulging, I see.
- 近來都餵養什麼  - 金髮女郎
- What you been feeding this thing?  - Blondes.
那我想它八成沒吃飽
I think it's still hungry.
豪瑟 你還有臉跑來這裡
You got a lot of nerve showing your face around here, Hauser.
這句話應該是我說的才對
Look who's talking.
東尼 別再煩他了
Hey, Tony, give the big guy a break.
放輕鬆點 如此才活得久
Relax. You'll live longer.
來吧
Come on.
- 親愛的 替我去招待東尼好嗎  - 沒問題
- Honey, take care of Tony, will you?  - No problem.
如果你應付不了這一個 就喊我一聲
If you need any help with this one, give me a holier.
你這狗娘養的
You son of a bitch.
你還活著 我都以為你被柯黑根折磨死了
You're alive? I thought that Cohaagen tortured you to death.
我想他大概沒這麼做吧
Well, I guess he didn't.
而你卻無法傳個口信給我 你難道都沒關心過我的死活
And you couldn't get me a message? You never wondered what happened to me?
豪瑟 謝天謝地 你還活著
Hauser, thank God you're alive.
梅琳... 梅琳娜 梅琳娜
Melin... Melina. Melina.
- 梅琳娜 我有話要告訴你  - 什麼事
- Melina, I have to tell you something.  - What?
- 我已經不記得你了  - 你在胡說些什麼
- I don't remember you.  - What are you talking about?
我不記得你了
I don't remember you.
我不記得我們之間的事 我甚至不記得我自己的過去
I don't remember us. I don't even remember me.
你得了失憶症 你是如何找來這裡的
Did you get amnesia? How did you get here?
- 豪瑟留給我一張字條  - 豪瑟 你就是豪瑟
- Hauser left me a note.  - Hauser? You're Hauser.
已經不是了
Not anymore.
我現在是奎德 道格拉斯·奎德
Now I'm Quaid. Douglas Quaid.
豪瑟 你精神錯亂了
Hauser, you've lost your mind.
我沒有精神錯亂 柯黑根偷了我的記憶
I didn't. Cohaagen stole it.
他發現豪瑟企圖背叛他 於是將他變成另一個人 變成我
He found out that Hauser switched sides, so he turned him into somebody else: me.
這故事太玄了
This is too weird.
再把我丟在地球上 給我一個老婆和一份爛工作
He dumped me on earth with a wife and a lousy job...
你說你有老婆 你他媽的結婚了
Did you say wife? Are you fucking married?
- 她其實不是我真正的太太  - 她不是你真正的太太
- She wasn't really my wife.  - Oh, she isn't?
我可真笨 她是豪瑟的太太
How stupid of me. She was Hauser's wife?
- 聽著 忘了我提到老婆的事  - 一切都別再說了
- Look. Forget that I said wife.  - Let's just forget everything.
- 我受夠了你和你那些謊言  - 我為何要騙你
- I'm sick of hearing your goddamn lies.  - Why would I lie to you?
因為你仍在為柯黑根工作
Because you're still working for Cohaagen.
別胡說了
Don't be ridiculous.
你根本就沒愛過我 豪瑟
You never loved me, Hauser.
你只想利用我 好混進去
You just used me to get inside.
混進什麼裡面
Inside what?
我看你還是走吧
I think you'd better leave.
- 梅琳娜 豪瑟派我來做某件事  - 我可不會上當
- Hauser sent me to do something.  - I'm not falling for it.
他說這腦袋裡裝的東西足以整垮柯黑根
He says there's enough in here to nail Cohaagen for good.
- 滾  - 你得幫我恢復記憶
- Get out!  - You've got to help me remember!
- 我叫你滾  - 梅琳娜 求求你
- I said, get out!  - Melina, please!
有人要殺我啊
People are trying to kill me.
真的
Really?
好吧 我這就走
All right, I'm leaving.
寶貝 你讓我恨不得能有三隻手
Baby, you make me wish I had three hands.
我想你這兩隻手已經很夠用了
I think you're doing just fine with two.
失陪一下 寶貝 咱們待會再聊
Excuse me, baby. We'll pick this up later.
兄弟 你不怎麼持久啊
Hey, that didn't take long.
聽著 我問你 你玩過變種妞嗎
Listen. Let me ask you a question. Did you ever fuck a mutant?
- 送我回飯店去  - 我認識一對變種雙胞胎
- Take me to the hotel.  - I know these Siamese twins.
保證讓你爽歪歪
Man, you won't know if you're coming or going.
今天下午四點半時 我簽署一份法令
This afternoon at 4:30pm, I signed an order declaring martial law
批准在火星聯邦自治區實施戒嚴
throughout the Mars federal colony.
我將不會再容忍任何破壞礦物輸出的行為
I will not tolerate any further damage to our mineral export operations.
寡頭先生和他手下的恐怖份子必須明白一件事
Mr Kuato and his terrorists must understand
他們這種自取毀滅的行為 只會為人民帶來苦難和痛苦...
that their self- defeating efforts will only bring misery and suffering...
- 奎德先生  - 什麼事
- Mr Quaid?  - What?
我要跟你談談 是關於豪瑟先生的事
I need to talk to you about Mr Hauser.
- 你是誰  - 瑞可公司的艾吉馬醫生
- Who are you?  - Dr Edgemar from Recall.
- 你是如何找到我的  - 解釋起來有點複雜
- How did you find me?  - It's difficult to explain.
你能開門嗎 我沒有帶武器
Could you open the door? I'm unarmed.
別擔心 我是一個人來的 我可以進去嗎
Don't worry. I'm alone. May I come in?
你來做什麼
What do you want?
你聽了後 可能會有點難以接受
This is going to be very difficult for you to accept, Mr Quaid.
- 我在聽  - 你此時恐怕不是真的站在這裡
- I'm listening.  - You're not really standing here now.
- 醫生 你差點就騙過我了  - 我可是說正經的
- Doc, you could have fooled me.  - I'm quite serious.
你不在這裡 我也不在
You're not here and neither am I.
這倒新鮮
That's amazing.
- 我們又是在哪  - 在瑞可公司
- Where are we?  - At Recall.
你被綁在一張手術椅上
You're strapped into an implant chair,
而我則透過精神追蹤探針 觀察你的情形
and I'm monitoring you from the psychoprobe console.
我明白了 原來我是在做夢
Ah, I get it. I'm dreaming.
而這一切全是貴公司賣給我的刺激的假期的一部份
And all this is part of the delightful vacation your company has sold me.
不完全是
Not exactly.
你目前所經歷的 全是根據我們製作的記憶母帶
What you're experiencing is a free-form delusion
所自由創造出來的幻象
based on our memory tapes
你將不斷地發展出新的情節
but you're inventing it yourself as you go along.
假設這是我創造出來的幻象 那麼又是誰請你來的
If it is my delusion, who the hell invited you?
我被植入這程式 以便發生狀況時能加以補救
I've been artificially implanted as an emergency measure.
我不得不告訴你 奎德先生 你在手術中出現精神分裂症
I'm sorry to tell you this, but you've suffered a schizoid embolism.
我們無法讓你從幻想中醒來
We can't snap you out of your fantasy,
於是我被派來 看看是否能勸你回到現實世界
and I've been sent in to try to talk you down.
柯黑根付你多少錢來幹這種事
How much is Cohaagen paying you for this?
你想想看 你的夢是在植入的過程中開始的
Think about it. Your dream started in the middle of the implant procedure.
那以後發生的一切 包括追殺 到達火星
Everything after that, the chases, the trip to Mars,
住宿於希爾頓飯店 全是瑞可公司提供你的自我旅行情節
the suite at the Hilton, are elements of your Recall Holiday and Ego Trip.
你付錢來扮演秘密情報員
You paid to be a secret agent.
狗屁 這不過是巧合罷了
Bullshit. It's coincidence.
那麼那個女孩呢
And what about the girl?
褐髮 運動員體型 既放蕩又端莊
Brunette, athletic, sleazy and demure?
完全符合你所指定的特徵 這也是巧合嗎
Just as you specified. Is that coincidence?
她是真的存在的 我在去瑞可之前就夢見過她了
She's real. I dreamt about her before I even went to Recall.
奎德先生...
Ha, Mr Quaid.
你知道你這邏輯有多荒唐嗎 你夢見過她 所以她是真的
Can you hear yourself? She's real because you dreamed her?
- 沒錯  - 或許這將能使你信服...
- That's right.  - Maybe this will convince you.
你能把門打開嗎
Would you mind opening the door?
- 你去開  - 沒有必要動粗 我來開好了
- You open it.  - No need to be rude. I'll do it.
親愛的
Sweetheart?
進來吧 奎德太太
Come in, Mrs Quaid.
我猜你此時也不是真的在此了
I suppose you're not here either.
我在這裡... 在瑞可公司
I'm here... at Recall.
我愛你
I love you.
是啊 所以你才會想殺我
Right. That's why you tried to kill me.
不 我絕不會做任何傷害你的事
No. I'd never do anything to hurt you.
我要你回到我的身邊
I want you to come back to me.
- 狗屁  - 什麼才是狗屁 奎德先生
- Bullshit.  - What's bullshit, Mr Quaid?
是你的細胞受到精神化學損傷
That you're having a paranoid episode
而引發一連串偏執的幻想
triggered by acute neurochemical trauma?
還是你真的是一個來自火星的臥底秘密情報員...
Or that you're really an invincible secret agent from Mars,
受到一項星際陰謀的迫害 讓你自以為是個...
who's the victim of an interplanetary conspiracy to make him think
卑微的建築工人
he's a lowly construction worker?
別再折磨你自己了 道格
Stop punishing yourself, Doug.
你是個正直的好人 你有個深愛著你的美麗妻子
You're a fine, upstanding man. You have a beautiful wife who loves you.
你還有許多美好的日子要過
Your whole life is ahead of you.
但你得先願意回到現實的世界
But you've got to want to return to reality.
就算我願意好了... 我又該怎麼做
Let's assume I do. Then what?
- 把這個吞下去  - 這是什麼
- Swallow this.  - What is it?
它是一個象徵 表示你願意回到現實的世界
It's a symbol of your desire to return to reality.
在你的夢裡 你將睡著
Inside your dream, you'll fall asleep.
好吧 假設你說的全是事實 這一切全是一場夢
All right, let's say you're telling the truth and this is all a dream.
那我大可扣下扳機 反正也不要緊
Then I could pull this trigger and it won't matter.
- 道格 別這麼做  - 這對我不會有什麼差別 道格
- Doug, don't.  - It won't make a difference to me.
但對你卻會有毀滅性的結果 在你的腦海裡 我將喪命
But the consequences to you would be devastating. In your mind I'll be dead.
在無人引導你走出的情況下 你將陷入永久的精神錯亂
With no one to guide you out, you'll be stuck in permanent psychosis.
道格 讓艾吉馬醫生幫助你
Doug, let Dr Edgemar help you.
現實世界的牆將整個倒塌
The walls of reality will come crashing down.
在前一分鐘裡 你還是拯救叛軍的大英雄
One minute you'll be the saviour of the rebel cause,
但接下來 你又將是柯黑根的心腹爪牙
and the next thing you know you'll be Cohaagen's bosom buddy.
你甚至將如你當初所要求的 幻想在太空中發現外星文明
You'll even have fantasies about alien civilisations, as you requested,
但在你終於回到現實世界後 你將被切除腦前葉
but in the end, back on earth you'll be lobotomised!
所以還是理智點 道格 把槍放下
So get a grip on yourself, Doug, and put down that gun!
很好 現在把那粒膠囊放進嘴裡
Good. Now take the pill and put it in your mouth.
吞下去
Swallow it!
吞下去 親愛的
Go ahead, sweetheart.
看看你幹了什麼好事 看你幹了什麼好事
Now you've done it. Now you've done it!
這是回敬你害我跑來火星
That's for making me come to Mars.
你知道我有多痛恨這個爛星球
You know how much I hate this fucking planet!
把他銬起來
Cuff him.
- 我抓住他了  - 好極了 用服務電梯將他送下來
- I got him.  - Bring him down in the service elevator.
我們走
Let's go.
去你的
FUCK you!
道格
Doug
親愛的
Honey...
親愛的 你不會傷害我 對不對
You wouldn't hurt me, would you, sweetheart?
親愛的 理智點
Sweetheart, be reasonable.
畢竟咱們是夫妻啊
After all, we're married.
現在離婚了
Consider that a divorce.
她就是你的老婆
That was your wife?
好一個賤人
What a bitch.
閃一邊去
Hey, get out of the way!
我還以為你不喜歡我
I thought you didn't like me.
如果柯黑根要殺你 你就應該沒問題
If Cohaagen wants you dead, you might be OK.
- 找到了  - 那麼你是回來向我道歉的
- Got it.  - So you've come back to apologise.
寡頭要見你
Kuato wants to see you.
快走
Come on.
- 現在怎麼辦  - 跳
- Now what?  - Jump!
不 別開槍 你會把圓頂打破的
No! Don't do it! You'll crack the fucking dome!
如果你這麼做 咱們全都會沒命 圓頂會破裂的
What are you trying to do, kill us? The dome will crack!
走開
Move!
計程車
Taxi!
梅琳娜 梅琳娜
Melina! Melina!
- 要坐車嗎  - 快 到終極樂園
- Need a ride?  - Last Resort. Quick!
你們這些人盡在兜圈子
You guys are going in circles.
我的天
Jesus!
快點 你開車
Come on! You drive!
你們是惹上了什麼麻煩
You guys are in trouble?
開車 開車
Go! Go!
- 兄弟 你是想害死我  - 閉嘴 開你的車就行了
- What are you trying to do to me?  - Shut up and drive!
我還有五個孩子要養啊
Hey, I got five kids to feed!
糟了
Shit!
- 車失靈了  - 停車
- No brakes! Ah!  - Stop it!
你這個白癡
You idiot!
你在幹什麼啊
What are you doing?
我的天 現在他們也要殺我了
Oh, Christ! Now they're after me!
把槍給我
Give me that!
滾一邊去
Get out of the way!
東尼
Tony!
別擋路 快來
Get out of the way! Come on!
快 快
Come on! Come on!
快
Quick!
謝謝你 東尼
Thank you, Tony.
你要... 樂一下嗎
Hey! You wanna have some fun?
他們在哪裡
Where are they?
你在說什麼啊 我不知道
What are you talking about? I don't know.
或許你知道
Maybe you know.
把他們都宰了
Kill them all!
桑蔔琳娜
Thumbelina!
瑞克特
Richter!
- 柯黑根打電話找你  - 我是瑞克特
- A call from Cohaagen!  - Richter here.
- 我們壓制住他們了  - 停止戰鬥 將人員撤出
- We've got them pinned down.  - Stop fighting and pull out.
但他們藏匿奎德 還保護他
But they've got Quaid. They're protecting him.
好極了 立刻撤出G區
Perfect. Get out of Sector G now.
別想
Don't think.
- 照辦就是了  - 是 長官
- Do it!  - Yes, sir.
將人員撤回
Pull 'em out.
所有人員撤退
Everybody, pull out!
快
Move!
- 柯黑根要將這一區封死  - 快來 班尼
- Cohaagen's sealing off the area!  - Come on, Benny!
第一代的移民埋骨于此
The first settlers are buried here.
他們苦幹到死 但財富卻全落到柯黑根手裡
They worked themselves to death, but Cohaagen ended up with all the money.
他替他們建廉價的圓頂 讓他們的後代變成畸形人
He built cheap domes and watched the kids turn into freaks.
我見過他們了
I saw them.
如果你想呼吸 還得跟他買空氣
And if you want to breathe, you have to buy his air.
或許你能改變這一切
Maybe you can change all that.
我想我的爺爺可能也埋在這裡
Hey, I think my grandpa might be here.
我能做什麼
So what can I do?
寡頭將讓你想起當你還是豪瑟時所知道的事
Kuato's gonna make you remember some things you knew when you were Hauser.
- 比方說什麼  - 各種的事
- Like what?  - All sorts of things.
- 或許你會想起你曾愛過我  - 這倒不需要寡頭的幫忙
- Maybe you'll remember you loved me.  - I don't need Kuato for that.
從什麼時候開始的
Since when?
別動
Freeze!
來吧 梅琳娜
Come on, Melina.
寡頭在等了
Kuato's waiting.
我找不到我的爺爺 但是...
I didn't find Grandpa, but...
我的媽呀
Oh, shit.
- 這傢伙是誰  - 是他幫助我們逃走的
- Who's this?  - He helped us get away.
你們無須擔心我 兄弟 我是站在你們這邊的
Hey, don't worry about me, man. I'm on your side.
原來你是個變種人 是吧
You're a mutant, huh?
好吧 我們走
All right, let's go.
- 你有試過將門炸開嗎  - 你在這裡等 跟我來
- Have you tried ramming down the door?  - You wait here. Follow me.
這麼做也是沒用的
It won't do any good.
- 柯黑根已經將通道減壓  - 那就打通往M區的路
- Cohaagen depressurised the tunnels.  - Then drill through to Section M.
我們辦不到 空氣已快耗盡了
We can't. We're running out of air.
我們需要援助
We need help.
再忍耐一下 梅琳娜剛剛帶著奎德到達此地
Sit tight. Melina just got here with Quaid.
我希望他值得我們如此犧牲
I hope he was worth it.
我也是
So do I.
- 很高興你們能及時趕來  - 你看來不怎麼高興
- I'm glad you made it.  - You don't look glad.
柯黑根封了維納斯城 還停止供應空氣
Cohaagen sealed up Venusville. He shut off the air.
你一定是知道某些重要的秘密 奎德
You must know something pretty important, Quaid.
他要你
He wants you.
如果我們不把你交出去 到了明早這一區的人都將沒命
If we don't hand you over, everybody in this sector will be dead by morning.
那麼咱們也沒什麼選擇的餘地了
Then we don't have much choice. Do we?
我們不能把他交出去
We can't turn him in.
這得讓寡頭來決定 跟我來吧 奎德
That's up to Kuato. Come with me, Quaid.
坐
Sit down.
- 寡頭在哪  - 在趕來此地的途中
- Where's Kuato?  - On his way.
你聽過關於金字塔礦場的傳聞吧
You heard the rumours about the Pyramid Mine?
是的
Yeah.
柯黑根在那裡面發現了某樣東西 讓他嚇得要命
Cohaagen found something weird inside and it's got him scared shitless.
什麼東西 外星人
What? Aliens?
- 你說呢  - 我不知道
- You tell me.  - I don't know.
是的 你知道 所以我們才把你弄來這裡
Yes, you do. That's why we brought you here.
柯黑根的大秘密...
Cohaagen's big secret is buried in that black hole
就埋在你的腦裡
you call a brain.
寡頭將要把它掘出來
And Kuato's gonna dig it out.
- 你就是寡頭 對吧  - 錯了
- You're Kuato, right?  - Wrong.
寡頭是個變種人 當你見到他時可別大驚小怪
Kuato's a mutant, so don't get upset when you see him.
奎德先生 你想要什麼
What do you want, Mr Quaid?
和你要的一樣 恢復記憶
The same as you. To remember.
但為了什麼
But Why?
- 為了能再成為我自己  - 你的所做所為決定你是什麼人
- To be myself again.  - You are what you do.
個人的價值在於他的所做所為
A man is defined by his actions...
而不是他的記憶
not his memory.
請握住我的雙手
Please take my hands.
現在 對我敞開你的心靈
Now open your mind to me.
拜託
Please.
敞開你的心靈...
Open your mind.
我們得在叛軍啟動它之前毀掉它
We should blow the thing up before the rebels turn it on.
我認為咱們可試著將它啟動 看看會有何結果
I say we throw the switch and see what happens.
- 別傻了  - 我們不能冒這種險
- Don't be an idiot.  - We can't risk it.
引發的連鎖反應 可能會毀掉這星球上所有的T礦
The chain reaction could spread to all the terbinium in the planet.
也就是熔毀 整個星球都可能會熔毀
That means a meltdown, a meltdown on a planetary scale.
你想造這玩意的人沒想到這點
Don't you think whoever built this thing thought of that?
誰曉得它們是怎麼想的 它們又不是人類
Who knows what the hell they thought? They weren't human.
或許這是個陷阱 或許它們就是要讓這星球熔毀
Maybe it's a trap. Maybe they want a meltdown.
我們甚至不知道這是否還能用
We don't even know if this piece of junk will work.
它的歷史有多久 一百萬年 五十萬年
What is it? A million? Half a million?
- 約有五十萬年  - 是五十萬年前造的
- About half a million.  - Half a million years old.
我們只需不讓寡頭...
Let's make sure Kuato...
醒醒 醒醒 快點 醒過來啊
Wake up! Wake up! Come on, wake up!
他們找到我們了 該死 我們走吧
They found us! Shit! Let's go!
快醒醒 清醒過來 快
Wake up! Snap out of it now! Come on!
- 他們殺進來了 大夥兒撤退  - 梅琳娜
- They found us! Everybody out!  - Melina!
快走 走啊
Get moving! Get out!
走啊
Get out!
大夥兒撤退 走啊
Everybody out! Get out!
到氣閘去 跟我來
Get to the air lock! Follow me!
班尼 快來啊
Benny, come on!
- 班尼  - 我來了
- Benny!  - I'm coming!
穿上太空衣 我們到外面去
Put these spacesuits on! We're going outside!
班尼 快點
Benny, hurry.
恭喜你 奎德 你終於帶領我們找到了他
Congratulations, Quaid. You led us right to him.
你怎能這麼做 你也是個變種人
How can you do this? You're a mutant.
- 我還有四個孩子要養  - 第五個到哪裡去了
- I got four kids to feed.  - So what happened to number five?
媽的 你終於抓到我的破綻了
Oh, shit, man. You got me.
我根本就還沒結婚
I ain't even married.
現在把手舉起來
Now put your fucking hands in the air!
奎德...
Quaid.
別白費力氣了 兄弟 他的算命生涯已經結束了
Forget it, man. His fortunetelling days are over.
啟動那個反應爐
Start the reactor.
解放火星
Free Mars.
柯黑根先生想跟你談談
Mr Cohaagen would like to talk to you.
原來這就是那位偉人
So this is the great man.
難怪他總能躲過我們的耳目
No wonder he kept out of sight.
我的好兄弟...
Well, my boy...
- 你是個英雄  - 去你的
- You're a hero.  - Fuck you.
不必謙虛 如今寡頭已經死了
Uh? Don't be modest. Kuato is dead.
叛軍已全部被消滅 而你則是最大的功臣
The resistance is completely wiped out, and you were the key to the whole thing.
他在騙人
He's lying.
你這該死的兩面派
You two-faced bastard.
別怪他 安琪兒 他的確是無辜的
Ha, ha. You can't blame him, angel. He's innocent.
是這樣的 奎德 我的手下沒有一個能接近寡頭
You see, Quaid, none of my people could get close to Kuato.
那些該死的變種人 總是能聞出我們的氣味
Fucking mutants could always sniff us out.
於是豪瑟和我經過一番思考後 將你創造出來
So Hauser and I sat down and invented you,
一個完美的臥底計畫
the perfect mole.
你根本就是睜眼說瞎話 豪瑟已經背叛了你
You know you're lying. Hauser turned against you.
我們就是要讓你這麼想的
That's what we wanted you to think.
事實是 豪瑟自願來扮演道格·奎德
The fact is, Hauser volunteered to become Doug Quaid.
唯有這方法才能騙過那些通靈人
It was the only way to fool the psychics.
別說笑了
Get your story straight.
自從我去過瑞可公司後 你手下這些白癡一直在追殺我
This idiot here has been trying to kill me ever since I went to Recall.
你怎麼可能要殺你派去臥底的人
You don't kill somebody you're trying to plant.
這並非計畫中的一部份 是你自己要去瑞可而壞了事
He wasn't in on it. You set him off by going to Recall.
- 那麼為何我還活著  - 我們一路上提供你許多幫助
- So why am I still alive?  - We gave you lots of help.
- 比方說班尼  - 這是我的榮幸 兄弟
- Benny here.  - My pleasure, man.
那個拿手提箱給你的人 面具 錢
The guy with the suitcase, the mask, the money,
以及豪瑟所留的話 這一切全是我們所安排的
the message from Hauser, all of that was set up by us.
抱歉 這說法太完美了
Sorry. Too perfect.
完美個屁
Perfect, my ass!
你在我們還沒來得及派你上場前 就開啟了你的記憶
You pop your memory cap before we can activate you.
讓瑞克特到處追殺你 破壞了我花了一年準備的計畫
Richter goes hog-wild, screwing up everything I spent a year planning.
老實說 這計畫能成功 連我都感到意外
Frankly, I'm amazed it worked.
柯黑根...
Well, Cohaagen,
我真是服了你 這是我所聽過最精彩的故事
I have to hand it to you. It's the best mind-fuck yet.
先別這麼快就下結論
Well, don't take my word for it.
- 某個你所信任的人要跟你說話  - 這一回又是誰 我母親
- Someone you trust wants to talk to you.  - Who is it this time? My mother?
你好 奎德
Howdy, Quaid.
如果你聽見這段話 就表示寡頭已死
If you're listening to this, it means that Kuato is dead
而你也帶領我們找到了他
and you have led us to him.
我就知道你一定不會讓我失望
I knew you wouldn't let me down.
抱歉讓你吃了這麼多苦頭 但朋友本來就該互相幫忙的
Sorry for the shit I've put you through, but hey, what are friends for?
我很想祝你永遠快樂 長命百歲 老朋友...
I would like to wish you happiness and long life, old buddy,
但不幸的是 這是不可能的
but unfortunately, this is not gonna happen.
要知道 你佔用的身體是我的 我現在得要回來
You see, it's my body you've got there and I want it back.
抱歉 有借就有還 那身體本來就是我的
Sorry to be an Indian giver, but I was here first.
那麼 永別了 朋友
So adios, amigo.
謝謝你沒讓自己送命
And thanks for not getting yourself killed.
或許咱們還會在夢裡見面呢
Hey, maybe we'll meet in our dreams.
誰曉得會怎樣
You never know.
你們這些混蛋
You bastards!
放開我
Let go of me!
- 準備好了  - 自動
- Ready?  - Auto.
- 全檢查過了  - 全準備好了 長官
- Check.  - Ready to go, sir.
放輕鬆點 奎德
Relax, Quaid.
- 你會喜歡當豪瑟的  - 那傢伙是個該死的混蛋
- You'll like being Hauser.  - The guy's a fucking asshole.
這不是真的 他是我最要好的朋友之一
Not true. He's one of my best friends.
更何況他有一棟大房子 一輛賓土汽車
Besides, he's got a big house and a Mercedes.
你喜歡梅琳娜 對吧 你今後每晚都可以幹她
And you like Melina, right? You'll get to fuck her every night.
是的 她將成為豪瑟的心肝寶貝
That's right. She's going to be Hauser's babe.
我會打爛他的卵蛋
I'll bust his balls.
不 公主...
Uh-uh, princess.
我們要將你改變一下
We're having you fixed.
你將學會尊敬 順從
You're going to be respectful, compliant
曉得感激 這些都是女人該具有的美德
and appreciative, the way a woman should be.
柯黑根先生 你的電話
Mr Cohaagen, telephone.
是的 什麼事
Yes? What is it?
長官 G區的氧氣已降到最低點
The oxygen level is bottoming out in Sector G.
你要我接下來怎麼做
What do you want me to do about it?
- 什麼也別做  - 但他們支持不到一個鐘頭了 長官
- Don't do anything.  - But they won't last an hour, sir.
讓他們去死 可以讓別區的人作為警戒
Fuck 'em. It'll be a good lesson to the others.
別這樣 柯黑根 你已達到你的目的 給這些人空氣吧
Come on, you got what you want. Give these people air.
我的朋友 再過五分鐘 你就不會關心這些人的死活了
My friend, in five minutes you won't give a shit about the people.
開始吧 醫生
Fire it up, Doc.
對不起 醫生
Excuse me, Doctor.
- 他將會記得這一切嗎  - 完全不會
- Is he gonna remember any of this?  - Not a thing.
真的
Oh, really?
奎德 我今晚要舉行派對 你可以帶梅琳娜一起來
Quaid, I'm having a party tonight. Why don't you and Melina drop by?
- 提醒他一下 醫生  - 我會的
- Remind him, Doc.  - Sure.
派對上見了
See you at the party.
別掙扎 你越反抗只會越痛苦
Keep still. Fighting just makes it hurt.
如果你不安靜下來 會精神錯亂的
If you don't keep still, you'll end up psychotic.
不
Hey, don't!
梅琳娜 支持住
Melina, hold on!
你還好吧 你仍是原來的你嗎
Are you all right? Are you still you?
我也不怎麼確定 親愛的 你想呢
I'm not sure, dear. What do you think?
咱們快離開這裡吧
Let's get the hell out of here.
你得做個決定才行 長官
You have to make a decision, sir.
殺了他
Kill him.
也該是時候了
It's about goddamn time.
- 你要上哪去  - 去找那反應爐
- Where are you going?  - To the reactor.
- 什麼反應爐  - 在礦坑裡的那個 快點
- What reactor?  - The one in the mines. Come on!
那些人都快死了啊 奎德 快停下來 我們得給他們空氣
People are dying, Quaid! Stop! We've got to get air!
那反應爐能製造空氣 這就是柯黑根的大秘密 我們走
The reactor makes air. That's Cohaagen's secret. Let's go.
這個反應爐又是從哪來的
Where's this reactor come from?
- 外星人造的  - 外星人
- Aliens built it.  - Aliens?
- 你確定它有用嗎  - 它就在前面
- Are you sure about this?  - It's just up ahead.
被封住了
What the hell?
奎德 奎德 你還記得我吧
Quaid! Hey, Quaid, you remember me?
是班尼 班尼就是我的名字
Benny! Benny's the name!
這個厲害
Oh, that's good!
我要把你們開膛破肚 我要把你們絞成肉泥
I'm gonna drill you, sucker! I'm gonna grind you up!
我來了
Ha-ha! I'm coming!
我來找你了 寶貝
I'm coming for you, baby!
這他媽的怎麼回事
What the fuck is this?
這個該死的火星廢物
Damn this piece of Martian junk!
奎德 我要把你壓扁
Hey, Quaid, I'm gonna squash you!
班尼 嘗嘗這個吧
Benny, here!
你他媽的在哪裡
Where the fuck are you?
我鑽死你
Screw you!
- 奎德 快到這邊來  - 什麼事
- Quaid, get over here!  - What is it?
- 這邊打通了一個缺口  - 我就知道
- There's an opening.  - I knew it.
這整個東西就是個以T礦製成的反應爐
This whole thing is one big reactor made out of terbinium.
柯黑根知道它可以製造氧氣 但那混蛋卻不肯將它啟動
Cohaagen knows it makes air. The bastard won't turn it on.
當然了 如果火星有了大氣層 他就無法再統治了
Of course not. If Mars had an atmosphere, he'd lose control.
看到那下面沒
See down there?
那是一條冰河
It's a glacier.
整個火星的核心都是冰
The whole core of Mars is ice.
反應爐把冰融化 就會釋放出氧氣來
The reactor melts it and it releases the oxygen.
來吧
Come on.
- 足夠讓所有的人呼吸  - 當然
- Enough for everyone to breathe?  - Sure.
足以供給整個星球使用
Enough for the whole planet.
如果咱們能及時將它啟動的話
If we turn it on in time.
上 快
Come on. Come on!
慢著
Hold on.
開槍
Now!
狗娘養的
Son of a bitch.
快退開
Move!
他身上有全息圖裝置
He's got a hologram!
你們以為這是真的奎德嗎 是真的
You think this is the real Quaid? It is.
我要死也要拉你墊背
You're coming with me!
派對上見了 瑞克特
See you at the party, Richter.
- 別碰那東西 退後  - 你怕什麼
- Don't touch that! Get back!  - What are you afraid of?
- 將它啟動啊  - 這是不可能的
- Turn it on.  - Impossible!
一旦連鎖反應產生 這星球上的T礦全將被毀
Once the reaction starts, it'll spread to all the terbinium in the planet.
整個火星也將熔毀
Mars will go into global meltdown.
所以外星人才從未使用過它
That's why the aliens never turned it on.
你以為我會相信你嗎
And you expect me to believe you?
誰在乎你相不相信 再過30秒你就沒命了
Who gives a shit what you believe? In 30 seconds you'll be dead.
然後我將炸了這個地方 回家去吃麥片
Then I'll blow this place up and be home in time for cornflakes.
我本來也不希望見到這種結局 我要豪瑟回來 但事與願違...
I didn't want it to end this way. I wanted Hauser back. But no.
你偏要當奎德
You had to be Quaid!
- 我本來就是奎德  - 你什麼也不是
- I am Quaid.  - You're nothing!
你什麼人也不是 只是一場愚笨的夢
You're nobody! You're a stupid dream.
所有的夢都是會結束的
Well, all dreams come to an end.
梅琳娜 別鬆手
Melina, hold on!
不 別這麼做 我們全都會死
Don't do it! We'll all die!
所有的人通通會死
Everybody will die!
奎德
Quaid!
我真不敢相信 這就像一場夢
I can't believe it. It's like a dream.
怎麼了
What's wrong?
我剛剛想到一個可怕的念頭
I just had a terrible thought.
如果這一切真的是一場夢呢
What if this is a dream?
那就趁夢醒前趕快吻我吧
Well, then kiss me quick before you wake up.